ABOUT ME

I'm a Social Data Scientist with a background in Political Science, applied quantitative methods, and programming in \P . A former PhD student in Political Science, I have extensive training in, and years of professional experience with, quantitative methods, spatial data analysis, and causal inference using non-experimental data. I have a passion for programming and data visualization as well as years of experience working in private, public, and political organizations. Beyond this, I am interested in politics, sports analytics, and the intersection between sport and politics. I love playing around with data to tell interesting and important stories and to present these visually. You can check out (some of) my work on my website or on \P .

EDUCATION

University of Copenhagen, MSc in Political Science

2021

- ► GPA: 11.7/12.0
- ► Specialization in Political Behavior and Advanced Quantitative Methods
- ► Relevant coursework: Managing and Analysing Cross Sectional and Spatial Data in Social Science, Advanced Quantitative Methods in the Study of Political Behavior, Design-Based Research in Criminology, Political Behavior

University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill, Visiting student

▶ Relevant coursework: Applied Econometric Analysis

University of Copenhagen, BSc in Political Science

2017

2018

- ► GPA: 9.1/12.0
- ► Relevant coursework: Research Methods I, Research Methods II, Advanced Quantitative Methods, Comparative Politics, Sociology

Professional Experience

Ministry of Higher Education and Science, Special Advisor

2024 -

- ▶ Employed as a Special Advisor in the Department's Analysis Office
- ▶ Working on the analytical and political dimensions of major governmental reform policies in the educational sector

Ministry of Children and Education, Head of Section

2022 - 2024

- ► I worked in the ministry's Department, specifically in the Center of Analysis and Structure
- ► Combined descriptive patterns, causal evidence, and substantial domain knowledge to promote evidence based policy development as well as providing empirical perspectives on the ministry's domains

▶ Performing econometric analyses of administrative registry data working in R and relying on advanced functional programming to write consistent, systematic, maintainable, and easily-adjustable code and utilizing Parallel Processing to reduce time consumption from working with extensive datasets ▶ Processing and assisting policy development and administrative workflows **Epinion**, Consultant 2021 - 2022▶ Worked as a consultant in the 'Transportation and Mobility' as well as the 'Epinion Analytics' unit ightharpoonup Applied quantitative methods \cdot Data visualization \cdot Package writing in R · Survey design and analysis University of Copenhagen, PhD fellow 2019 - 2021▶ Enrolled as a PhD fellow at the Department of Political Science. I studied how various forms of political authority shape(d) economic dynamics throughout history ▶ My work relied extensively on advanced quantitative methods coded in R, descriptive and causal inference and on granular spatial data ► Awarded a Fulbright Scholarship (\$14,000 grant) ▶ Taught a fifth-semester course on Danish and Comparative Politics. ▶ Relevant coursework: Advanced Quantitative Empirical Methods, Analyzing/Presenting Data/Information by Edward Tufte, The Logic of Quantitative Research, Mixed Methods Research, Research Designs 2019 University of Copenhagen, Graduate Research Assistant ▶ Hired by Professor Asmus Leth Olsen to create publication-ready graphics for a book publication ▶ Performed data wrangling and data visualization in R using ggplot2, ggridges etc. Diøf, Data Visualization Consultant 2019 ► Hired as part of the 'DJØF index' project, which combined polling data from various Danish polling agencies to predict the 2019 Danish parliamentary election ▶ Created daily visualizations of predicted vote shares at the bloc and party level in R using ggplot2, gganimate etc. 2019 Damvad Analytics, Quantitative Intern ▶ Full-time internship, worked on various projects for private and public sector clients. Tasks included everything from data

collection and analysis to creating presentations for clients

The Danish Society of Engineers (IDA), Junior Analyst

▶ Worked on various projects in close collaboration with the Chief Economist. Project manager for several analyses of membership survey data. Created an econometric analysis of membership attrition. Used MS Excel, R, and Stata

University of Copenhagen, Graduate Student Instructor

▶ Taught a third-semester class in 'Public Administration and Public Policy' at the Department of Political Science 2017 - 2019

Danish Metalworkers' Union, Student Assistant

2015 - 2016

▶ Worked in the President's Secretariat, assisting with analyses of labor union issues as well as industrial and research policy

The Danish Ministry of Employment, Student Assistant 2014 - 2015

▶ Worked in the communications department, assisting with redistribution of as well as written responses to citizens' inquiries

Programming Languages / Software

😱 (RStudio, Tidyverse, ggplot2, sf, RMarkdown, Shiny, devtools/usethis, purrr/furrr/future etc.) Stata · LATEX · git · GitHub · MS Office

SKILLS

Data Analysis Wrangling/cleaning · Visualization · Statistical modeling Descriptive and causal inference · Web scraping · Spatial Data Text-as-data · Package development · Functional programming Causal inference · Design-based research and natural experiments

R PACKAGES ON CRAN

— In progress —

R PACKAGES

dyadicdist · voters · repinion · epinionDSB

ON C

CERTIFICATES Project Management, Implement Consulting Group 2023

- ▶ Seven day course on general project management spanning Sept. - Nov. 2023
- ▶ Practical and theoretical exam passed in Nov. 2023

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Danish (native) · English (fluent) · Swedish (basic) · French (rudimentary) German (rudimentary)

PERSONAL INTERESTS Football (...and other sports) · Politics · Literature

Running · Cooking · Wine

ORGANZA-TIONAL EXPERIENCE PhD Program Committee, PhD Representative

2020 - 2021

▶ Part of the committee that runs the PhD program at the Department of Political Science

SUL, Board Member

2017 - 2019

▶ Board member of SUL, the National Labor Union for Graduate Student Instructors